KEVIN OZOMARO

Kevozomaro@outlook.com 209-715-7231

Summary

The focus of my research is currently in analyzing the relationship between media and public understanding of reality. My research incorporates an interdisciplinary methodology that includes rhetoric, mass media effects theory, focus groups and relational interviews. These diverse theoretical approaches help to illuminate the connection between media consumption and public understandings of reality. I have taught for five years at K-12 institutions, leading courses in public speaking, argumentation, and creative writing. I am currently teaching my second undergraduate speech and debate team as a graduate teaching assistant. I also work as a communication specialist for the University of the Pacific Alumni Association, Seeds of Growth Counseling, and the California Workforce Development Board. As a communication specialist I mange social media and company public image and relationships. I uses data analytics to make informed decisions, create communication best practice, analyzing competitors, synthesizing business intelligence and evaluating trends to enhance business results. Forward-thinking and enterprising when meeting expected demands with real-time data and strategic recommendations. Natural leader with resourceful and systematic approach.

Skills

- Social media management
- Team development
- Professional business writing
- Event coordination

- Gap analysis
- Data collection and analysis
- Analytical mindset
- Copywriting abilities

Experience

10/2021 - Current California Workforce Development Board Sacramento, CA

Student Communication Specialist Communication Data Analytics

- Identified and analyzed social media strategy implications for growing online public engagement.
- Prepared forecasts and identified trends through data analysis and tracking.
- Developed automation for social media analytics tracking.
- Analyzed market data to determine and target key audience or segments.
- Performed competitor analysis to identify high-value keyword and backlink options.
- Work independently and as a team to create communication content for social media and the company website.
- Maintain effective and beneficial relationships with internal and external customers

Website Development and Maintenance

- Followed internal procedures for HTML script standards to create reliable, reusable assets.
- Reviewed information and elements regularly on websites and pages for accuracy and functionality.
- Improved and designed new layouts to achieve usability and performance objectives.
- Troubleshot, tested and remedied issues before page deployment.

Accessibility

Support accessibility knowledge base and company-wide

08/2021 - Current

accessibility requirements.

- Review document designs and templates to increase the ease of exporting accessible materials.
- Successful remediation of DOC, PDF, and Websites.

Communications Specialist

University of the Pacific Alumni Association Sacramento, CA

Social Media

- Managed multiple projects and tasks simultaneously while managing client expectations.
- Wrote social media content to increase engagement with customers.
- Tracked and analyzed social media and online marketing initiatives.
- Utilized Twitter and Facebook to promote products, services and content.

Social Media Analyst

- Planned and executed social media marketing campaigns to promote brand engagement.
- Monitored replies and comments to expertly assess criticism, complaints and concerns of current and prospective customers and consumers.
- Referenced charts and reports to optimize and refocus social media campaigns.
- Analyzed market data to determine and target key audience or segments.

Event Coordination

- Organized luncheons, dinners, conferences and special events.
- Designed and maintained spreadsheets documenting vendor, facility and guest information.
- Recommended money-saving strategies for events to bring costs within budget.
- Oversaw main database and thorough alumni records.
- Managed social media accounts by composing content, engaging with followers in comments, monitoring activities and researching trends.

09/2020 - Current University of the Pacific Stockton, CA

Graduate Forensics Assistant Coach

- Created and utilized training drills to improve team cohesiveness and performance.
- Assisted coach in organizing practices at home and away.
- Notified head coach of problems with discipline, performance and other decision-making areas.
- Developed strategies for each match based on knowledge of opposing team and individual player strengths.
- Worked with with administration to stay on top of changes and concerns.

09/2021 - 05/2022 University of the Pacific Writing Center Stockton, CA

Graduate Copyeditor

Editing

- Proofread and reviewed print and electronic content for correct grammar and adherence to house style.
- Edited documents and assessed copy for grammar issues, delivering error-free materials to clients.
- Participated in monthly copy editors' meeting and reviewed, updated and revised editing guidelines.

Graduate Writing Tutor

- Creating comfortable tutoring environment conducive to learning.
- Assisted students in finding useful study methods to enhance academic performance.
- Provided one-on-one and group tutoring instruction for over 20 students.
- Supported student learning with live video sessions and pre-recorded instructions.

06/2021 - 12/2021 Seeds of Growth Consulting Sacramento, CA

Social Media Manager

- Remained up to date about the latest social media technology and platforms
- Recorded data regarding website traffic and user feedback
- Assisted with management of client presence on varying social media platforms
- Oversaw new product shoots for Instagram posts.
- Utilized Twitter and Facebook to promote products, services and content.
- Analyzed market data to determine and target key audience or segments.

01/2021 - 12/2021 Seeds of Growth

Web Developer

• Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements

Consulting
Sacramento, California

- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout
- Managed front-end and back-end development in the company's Portfolio Analyst, Employee Track, and Account Management systems.
- Designed websites, portals and large-scale web applications for multiple clients.
- Created dynamic web apps using PHP and MySQL to suit individual client needs.

Education and Training

Stockton, CA

Expected in 05/2022 Master of Arts in Communication Studies

University of The Pacific

05/2020 Sacramento, CA

Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies

California State University

05/2017 Stockton, CA

Associate of Arts in Communication Studies

San Joaquin Delta College

Expected in 05/2022 Stockton, CA

Associate of Science in Computer Science

San Joaquin Delta College

Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Google Data Analytics

Activities and Honors

National Communication Association (NCA) Western States Communication Association (WSCA) Northern California Forensics Association (NCFA) National Forensic Association (NFA) National Debate Coaches Association (NDCA)

Accomplishments

- Social Movement Pluralism: An investigation of Stockton Stands with Minneapolis panel for 2021 Student Research & Creative Activity Spring Symposium
- Ocial Movement Pluralism: An investigation of Stockton Stands with Minneapolis panel for Western States Communication Association Communication Theory
- Frican American Socialization: The missing variable to recruitment and retention panel for Western States Communication Association Organizational Communication Studies
- Apping Cultural Appropriation and Exploitation through HBO's Lovecraft Country panel for Western States Communication Association Rhetoric and Critical Analysis

Additional Information

• Forensic Achievements 1st place in junior Lincoln-Douglas Debate at NCFA 5th place Open Extemporaneous Speaking at NCFA Quarter Finalist in Lincoln-Douglas Debate at NCFA Quarter Finalist in Parliamentary Debate at NCFA Silver Medalist in Parliamentary Debate at C.C.C.F.A. Bronze Medalist in Parliamentary Debate at C.C.C.F.A 2nd place LD Debate the Golden Gate Opener at SFSU 5-1 (semifinalist, 8th speaker) The Ocho at Lafayette 3-1 2nd Place the Biggest Little City Classic at UNR 4-0 (Tournament Champion!! 4th Speaker) The Paul Winters Invitational at UOP 4-0 Tournament Champion The Steinbeck Classic at Hartnell 4-2 (Second Place) The Gorlok Gala at Webster University 4-0 (2nd Place, Top Speaker) The Talk Hawk at Las Positas College 2017 NCFA Outstanding LD Debater at a 4-year University Academic Awards 2020-2021 University of the Pacific Outstanding Forensics Graduate Assistant

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

Kut.cards